A Guide to the Gwathmey Family Papers, 1790-1982
Virginia Historical Society
- Mary Burnley Gwathmey (1883-1974), "Burlington," King William County, Va., and New York, N.Y. 1910-1974
  - General correspondence, 1910-1917 (Box 47-48)
  - Other correspondence, and financial records, 1916-1974 (Box 48 (cont.))
    Correspondence with institutions, 1916-1973; letters of recommendation; greeting cards; accounts, 1934-1974; financial records, 1930-1974.
  - Art and design materials, 1924-1959 (Box 49-51)
    University of Arkansas, 1924-1925; Columbia University, 1926-1943; design consultant, 1928-1936; Washington-Lee High School, 1943-1959; Virginia 350th Anniversary Commission, 1953-1958; speeches; biographical; clippings; magazine articles; notebooks; notes; miscellany.
  - Organizations and projects, 1921-1959 (Box 52)
    Red Cross, 1921; Switzerland, 1931; Syvlia Hill, 1943-1959; King William 250th Anniversary Committee, 1952-195?.
  - Beulah Baptist Church materials, 1936-1967 (Box 53)
    Beulah Baptist Church, 1961-1967 and minute books, 1812-1843, 1936-1952; scrapbooks; directory; memoranda book; essays and lines of verse
  - Other papers. (Box 54)
    Genealogical notes; clippings; miscellany; estate
- Miscellaneous Family and Unidentified Materials. (Box 55)
  Mollie Burnley; Eleanor Gwathmey, 1842-1931; John Hill Gwathmey, 1798-1839; Joseph Hardin Gwathmey, 1878-1945; Washington Gwathmey; William Gwathmey, 1875-1920; William Henry Gwathmey, 1819-1886; Mary Overton (Burnley) Meaux; Anna Maria (Garnett) Ryland, 1826-1951; John Newton Ryland; unidentified and family; miscellany.